# **JORAM APE**

Brgy, Furtune town Bacolod City, Negros Occidental 09469548685

akocjoram@gmail.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I would like to utilize my skills and experiences. And to work with other professionals to improve my skills as an IT professional which will allow me to further contribute in the field of information technology.

#### **PROFITE**

Dedicated IT professional with 2+ years of experience providing IT support and maintenance for on-site and remote pc using vnc, troubleshooting hardware and software, preform upgrades to peripheral equipment and backup Data to the server, Windows 2003 r2, hyper-v manager.

#### **EDUCATION**

Northern Negros State College of Science and Technology (NONESCOST) Bachelor of Science in Information Technology,

OLD SAGAY, SAGAY CITY 2014 - 2018

National Certificate II Computer system Servicing

Issued on: January 16, 2018 Valid until: January 15, 2023

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **NEW CITY BUILDER INC.**

IT STAFF

BACOLOD CITY, NEG, OCC

June 2022 - Present

- Performed LAN network, software and hardware troubleshooting and upgrade to ensure all systems were operating optimally.
- Install and configures, computers, laptops, printers and other devices
- Installing operating system windows 7,8,10 and printers Hp, Epson.
- All IT equipment's Inventory and request.
- Register staff Bio-metric and manage daily in/out record of workers.
- Installing CCTV and crimping RJ45.
- Technical support to the officemate.

## **GAISANO GRAND MALL**

**BACOLOD CITY, NEG, OCC** 

November 2019 – June 2022

#### **INFOTECH**

- Investigate and respond to support requests via email, phone and making Technical Inventory.
- Networking and Database management and administration.
- Installing operating system windows 7,8,10 and printers canon, hp and Epson, wincor/Nixdorf ND77 IBM iSeries Access for windows / Emulator
- Install and configures, computers, laptops, printers and other devices for 8 Department.
- Troubleshooting and maintenance of POS machines, Windows Server 2003 R2, hyper-v manager and backup Sales data daily.
- Perform hardware and software upgrades to peripheral equipment
- Performed network, software and hardware troubleshooting and upgrade to ensure all systems were operating optimally.
- Reading and troubleshooting bank terminal (BDO,BPI,METROBANK,PAYMAYA)

## **TELEQUEST VOICE SERVICE**

**IT Support** 

July - November 2018

- Performed network, software and hardware troubleshooting to ensure all systems and 4 workstations were operating optimally
- Installing and Configured Windows 7,8,10
- setup workstation and cabling configure switch crimping UTP RJ45,
- Investigate and respond to support requests via email, phone and making Technical Inventory.

# **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

- HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL xampp
- Proficient Windows 7,8,10, Microsoft Office
- Cabling UTP cable, Installing OS

## **SEMINARS AND TRANINGS**

- Startup Company March 10, 2017
- BPO

March 10, 2017

Information Security

August 5, 2017

Fundamental of Research and Statistics

August 6, 2017

Web Framework

August 7, 2017

• PhilNits Orientation

August 9, 2017

• Geographical Information System

August 12-13, 2017

• Android Development

August 20, 2017

• Campus DeVcon

March 1, 2018